Guide to the Archie Ammons papers,1945-2010.
Ammons, Archie papers, 1945-2010.
- Series IV. Correspondence
  - Other Correspondence, A-Z
    - Ryser, Darcy - Schimmel, Harold (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Schneider, Steven (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Schnitzer, Lisa - Schuester, Janet (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Schultz, Robert (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Schwartz, Dan - Sebastian, Robert (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Sedgwick, Eve (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Seldin, Harriet - Seton Hall University (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Sewanee Review (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - Sexton, Tom - Shelton, Don (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - Shenandoah (Box 51, Folder 10)
    - Sheperd, G. F. - Sinos, Dale (Box 51, Folder 11)
    - Sitter, John (Box 51, Folder 12)
    - The Sixties - Skezas (Box 51, Folder 13)
    - Slate Magazine (Box 51, Folder 14)
    - Slatoff, James - Snider, Neil (Box 51, Folder 15)
    - Soifer, Mark (Box 51, Folder 16)
    - Solis, Armando - Southern Methodist University (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Southern Poetry Review (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Southern Review (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - South Florida Community College (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Staples, Beth - Steinmen, Lisa (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Stephenson, Shelby (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Stephens, Mona - Szigeti, William (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Taggart, John - Terranova (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - Texas, University of, at El Paso (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Trellis - Tyler, James (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Uchida, Kyoko - Van Dias, Robert (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Vassar College (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Vaughn, Stephanie, January 24, 1986-September 3, 1996 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - Vencia, Pasquale (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - Vendler, Helen, January 7, 1974-May 1996 (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - Vette, Jean - Wakefield, Joyce (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - Wake Forest University, September 27, 1971-March 19, 1997 (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - Wakoski, Diane - Walters, Wendy S. (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - Walthall, Hugh, n.d., July 30, 1975-March 1979 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Walman, Albert - Western Michigan University (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Whelen, Christopher - Who's Who in the East (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Wieder, Laurence - Williams, Gil (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Williams, Jonathan - Willoughby, Dylan (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Wilson, Emily and Edward, September 24, 1974-January 27, 1995 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Wilson, Larry - Working Papers (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Worth, Douglas - Wyche, Melba (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Yale Review, November 11, 1988-September 29, 1992 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Yale University - Zomparelli, Wendy (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence 1997-2000
    - 1951-1997 and undated (Box 114, Folder 1)
    - April-June 1997 (Box 114, Folder 2)
    - July 1997 (Box 114, Folder 3)
    - October 1997 (Box 114, Folder 4)
    - December 1997 (Box 114, Folder 5)
    - 1998 (Box 114, Folder 6)
    - March 1998 (Box 114, Folder 7)
    - July 31, 1998-May 1999 (Box 114, Folder 8)
    - January-June 1999 (Box 114, Folder 9)
    - July-September 1999 (Box 114, Folder 11)
    - October-December 1999 (Box 114, Folder 12)
    - January-May 1999 (Box 114, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence [1974]1997-2001, A-Z
    - Arnesen, Ingrid, January 17, 2001-February 19, 2001 (Box 119, Folder 1)
    - Baird, Ansie, March 31, 1999-December 5, 2000 (Box 119, Folder 2)
    - Beriachetto, Sara and Bond, Cynthia, 1998-January 2001 (Box 119, Folder 3)
    - Brandt, Florence, May 18, 1998-October 13, 2001 (Box 119, Folder 4)
    - Burr Zofia and Carlson, C.A., June 2000-February 9, 2001 (Box 119, Folder 5)
    - Cooke, J. Robert and Corson, Dale, October 23, 1998-January 2001 (Box 119, Folder 6)
    - Gossett, Tom and Louise, May 21, 2000-January 5, 2001 (Box 119, Folder 7)
    - Greeting Cards, September 2000-February 2001 (Box 119, Folder 8)
    - Hewit, Greg and Highlights, August 25, 2000-January 31, 2001 (Box 119, Folder 9)
    - Hoffman, Roald and Hudson Review, May 8, 1985-February 3, 2001 (Box 119, Folder 10)
    - Lannan, October 17, 2000-January 26, 2001 (Box 119, Folder 11)
    - Lehman, David, January 1989-October 6, 2000 (Box 119, Folder 12)
    - Libraries, Magazines and Universities, September 9, 1997-April 11, 2001 (Box 119, Folder 13)
    - MacArthur Foundation, June 1, 1981-October 30, 1984 (Box 119, Folder 14)
    - McCoy, Maureen, May 21, 1998-December 12, 2000 (Box 119, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous, 1974, 19998, 19999, 2000, 2001 (Box 119, Folder 16)
    - Posthumous, March 20, 2001-August 9, 2001 (Box 119, Folder 17)
    - Schneider, Steven and Stephenson, Shelby, May 17, 2000-February 18, 2001 (Box 119, Folder 18)
    - The Academy of American Poets, September 28, 1998-July 8, 1999 (Box 119, Folder 19)
    - Willoughby, Dylan; Wilson, Edwin G.; Wilson, Emily H., May 15, 1998-February 2001 (Box 119, Folder 20)
  - Condolences
    - February 25-28, 2001, February 2001 (Box 120, Folder 1)
    - March 1-9, 2001, March 2001 (Box 120, Folder 2)
    - March 10-30, 2001, March 2001 (Box 120, Folder 3)
    - April 1-30, 2001, April 2001 (Box 120, Folder 4)
    - May 4, 2001-August 30, 2002, May 2001 - August 2002 (Box 120, Folder 5)
- Series V. Literary Manuscripts
  - Published
    - Collections of Poems
      - Tape for the Turn of the Year ts. on adding machine tape, 1963-1964 (Box 98)
      - Tape for the Turn of the Year (1965) See XII, Books and Magazines. Briefings (1971) ts., n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1)
      - Collected Poems (1972) proofs of index; ts., photocopy, two copies, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 2)
      - Sphere: The Form of a Motion (1974) ts., with editorial corrections, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 3)
      - Sphere: The Form of a Motion (cont'd) ts., titled: "Floating, Sphere, the Form of a Motion", n.d. (Box 56, Folder 4)
      - Diversifications (1975) ts., photocopies, with letter to John Benedict of Norton & Norton, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 5)
      - Diversifications (cont'd) ts., with publishers' correctionsmaster set, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 6)
      - Diversifications (cont'd) Master set, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 7)
      - The Snow Poems (1977) ts., carbons, with a few penciled corrections, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1)
      - The Snow Poems (cont'd), n.d. (Box 57, Folder 2)
      - The Snow Poems (cont'd) ts., photocopies, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 3)
      - The Snow Poems (cont'd) ts., photocopies, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 4)
      - Sumerian Vistas (1987) galley proofs (three copies), n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1)
      - Sumerian Vistas (cont'd) show proof, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1)
      - Sumerian Vistas (cont'd)blue prints, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 2)
      - Sumerian Vistas (cont'd) "Motion's Holdings" ts., carbons, photocopies, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 3)
      - The Really Short Poems (1990) ts., some photocopies, few dated, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1)
      - Garbage (cont'd) "Master pages", n.d. (Box 60, Folder 2)
      - Garbage (cont'd) "Master galleys", n.d. (Box 60, Folder 3)
      - Garbage (cont'd) ts. with publishers' corrections and a few printed pages, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 4)
      - Garbage (cont'd) "reprodupe", n.d. (Box 60, Folder 5)
      - Garbage (cont'd) ts. with handwritten corrections and notes, photocopy, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 6)
      - Brink Road (1996) ts., carbons and some photocopies, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1)
      - Brink Road (cont'd) ts., photocopies, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 2)
      - Brink Road (cont'd) ts., rejects, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 3)
      - Brink Road (cont'd) ts., rejects, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 4)
      - Glare (1997) ts., on long narrow strips of paper, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1)
      - Glare ts. with handwritten corrections, photocopy, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Poems Appearing in Magazines
      - Diacritics (Box 62, Folder 3)
      - Hudson Review (Box 62, Folder 4)
      - Mademoiselle (Box 62, Folder 5)
      - Ohio Review (Box 62, Folder 6)
      - Red Clay Reader (Box 62, Folder 7)
      - Two poems from The Cornell Crescent, Cornell football game program. A Priori and Reticulum of Indirection, November 8, 1986 (Box 62, Folder 8)
      - Photocopies of poems appearing in magazines, 1997-2001 (Box 123, Folder 2)
      - Photocopies of poems appearing in books, undated (Box 123, Folder 3)
    - Other Writings
      - [Editor of The Best American Poetry 1994 ] Selections, "Introduction" ts., Nov-93 (Box 63, Folder 1)
      - ts., galleys (1) (Box 63, Folder 2)
      - ts., galleys (2) (Box 63, Folder 3)
      - ts., galleys (3) (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Unpublished
    - >Loose Poems
      - [Loose poems] ts., various dates, most undated (Box 64, Folder 1-3)
      - [Loose poems, cont'd] (Box 65, Folder 1-4)
      - [Loose poems, cont'd] (Box 66, Folder 1-4)
      - [Loose poems, cont'd] ts. carbons (Box 67, Folder 1)
      - [Loose poems, cont'd] ts. carbons (Box 67, Folder 2)
      - [Loose poems, cont'd] ts. carbons (Box 67, Folder 3)
      - [Loose poems, cont'd] ts. carbons (Box 67, Folder 4)
      - [Loose poems] ts. (Box 68, Folder 1)
      - [Loose poems] ts. (Box 68, Folder 2)
      - [Loose poems] ts. (Box 68, Folder 3)
      - [Loose poems] ts. (Box 68, Folder 4)
      - [Loose poems] ts. (Box 68, Folder 5)
      - [Loose poems] ts., mostly undated, 1970, 1971 (Box 69, Folder 1)
      - [Loose poems] ts. (Box 69, Folder 2)
      - "No Use" ts., n.d. (Box 69, Folder 3)
      - "No Use" ts. (cont'd), n.d. (Box 69, Folder 4)
      - Poems on rolled-up narrow strips of paper, individually titled, part 16 and 18 of "Garbage", 1 roll of poems published in "Bosh and Flapdoodle." most undated; 1970-1971 (Box 70)
      - (cont'd), Roll 17 apparently from "Garbage." September-December 1975 (Box 71)
      - (cont'd), 1986-1996 (Box 72)
      - (cont'd), February-May 1977 (Box 73)
      - (cont'd), January-May, September-December 1976 (Box 74)
      - Poems on narrow flat strips of paper, ts., loose, most undated (Box 75)
      - Handwritten poems, loose, 1997-1998 (Box 122, Folder 6)
    - Grouped Poems
      - Grouped poems, in alphabetical order: "Untitled" ts., n.d. (Box 76, Folder 1)
      - "Clabberbabble" ts., n.d. (Box 76, Folder 2)
      - "Dispositions" ts., undated (Box 76, Folder 3)
      - "The Exactly Poems" ts., undated (Box 76, Folder 4)
      - "Form of a Motion" ts., n.d. (Box 76, Folder 5)
      - "Great Day in the Morning", n.d. (Box 76, Folder 6)
      - "Highgate Road" ts., n.d. (Box 77, Folder 1)
      - "How to Find Wisdom in Writing and Painting" ts., n.d. (Box 77, Folder 2)
      - "Improvisations" ts., n.d. (Box 77, Folder 3)
      - "Mostly Junk" ts., n.d. (Box 77, Folder 4)
      - "Mostly Junk" (cont'd), n.d. (Box 77, Folder 5)
      - "Mostly Junk" (cont'd), n.d. (Box 78, Folder 1)
      - "No Time Soon" ts., n.d. (Box 78, Folder 2)
      - "No Time Soon: Bosh and Flapdoodle" ts., n.d. (Box 78, Folder 3)
      - "Only So Many" ts., n.d. (Box 78, Folder 4)
      - "Packing Light" ts., n.d. (Box 78, Folder 5)
      - "Remington Road" ts., n.d. (Box 78, Folder 6)
      - "Shit Fire and Save Matches" ts., n.d. (Box 78, Folder 7)
      - "Short Notices" ts., n.d. (Box 78, Folder 8)
      - "Slush or Trash or Slime" ts., n.d. (Box 79, Folder 1)
      - "Sudden Moves" ts., n.d. (Box 79, Folder 2)
      - "Unscheduled Events" ts., n.d. (Box 79, Folder 3)
      - A.R. Ammons' poetry in music: musical scores, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 4)
      - Poems on index cards, the first of which is by Josephine Miles, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 5)
      - Bosh and Flapdoodle, undated (Box 122, Folder 1)
      - The Barely Rowdy Poems of A.R. Ammons Draft 1, undated (Box 122, Folder 2)
      - The Barely Rowdy Poems of A.R. Ammons Draft 2, undated (Box 122, Folder 3)
      - The Barely Rowdy Poems of A.R. Ammons Draft 3, undated (Box 122, Folder 4)
    - Bound Poems
      - Poems in binders: "Chrono I", Chrono II, first 6 pp. ms. jottings, then ts., poems with many corrections, November 3, 1957-December 26, 1961 (Box 80)
      - Chrono III, ts., with many jottings and corrections, arranged chronologically; Chrono IV, ts., with many jottings and corrections, arranged chronologically; January 20, 1962-February 6, 1965; January 12, 1965-May 7, 1971 (Box 81)
      - Chrono V, ts. with corrections and jottings, with notes of writing poetry and journal entries; initial poems variously dated, most in chronological orderOn cover: "Done Cantos." On first page: "Navigations"No cover title. On first page: "Fugue for the Turn of the Year"; ts., with few corrections and jottings, undated; consists of a single poem titled: "Today", February 25, 1971-August 9, 1975 mostly undatedDecember 6-7, 1963 (Box 82)
      - Jottings (Box 83)
    - Other Unpublished Writings
      - Autobiographical, ms., n.d. (Box 84, Folder 1)
      - Book Reviews, ts., n.d. (Box 84, Folder 2)
      - Essays ms. and ts., n.d. (Box 84, Folder 3)
      - Eulogy for Walter Slatoff, ts., n.d. (Box 84, Folder 4)
      - "The Mountain" [play], ts., undated (Box 84, Folder 5)
      - "A Future for Madam Gray" and "Kangaroo Rat," ts., undated (Box 84, Folder 6)
  - Combined Published and Unpublished or Unknown
    - Miscellaneous poems and correspondence, published and unpublished, 1972-1999 (bulk 1980s and 1998-1999) (Box 122, Folder 7-8)
    - "Core Sample," loose, t.s., rolled, undated (Box 122)
    - Numbered poems, undated (Box 123, Folder 1)
    - Photocopies of word processed poems, undated (Box 123, Folder 4)
    - Poems saved and typed by Amanda Moore, 1997-1998 (Box 123, Folder 5)
    - Poems saved and typed by Amanda Moore, 1997-1998, 2002 (Box 123, Folder 6)
      Title page reads "Bosh and Flapdoodle (Or Maybe No Time Soon)"
    - Typed Poems (typewriter and computer), 1997-1998 (Box 123, Folder 7)
    - Poems saved and typed by Amanda Moore, 2002; 3.5" floppy disk, FD-8 (Box 124)
- Series VI. Professional Activities
  - Editorial activities [Epoch] one ts. letter (Box 84, Folder 7)
  - Editorial activities (cont'd) The Nation ts. correspondence, galley proof (Box 84, Folder 8)
  - Editorial activities (cont'd) The New Yorker Magazine, one ts. letter] (Box 84, Folder 9)
  - Editorial activities (cont'd) Nickelodeon, photocopies of ts. issues] (Box 84, Folder 10)
  - Judge for poetry contests: 1968/1969 College Literary Magazine Awards; press release, correspondence, 1968/1969 (Box 84, Folder 11)
  - Judge for poetry contests (cont'd): Harriet Monroe Prize, 1990, 1990 (Box 84, Folder 12)
  - Judge for poetry contests (Cont): The Avery Hopwood and Julie Hopwood Poetry Awards, 1969, 1969-1974 (Box 84, Folder 13)
  - Introductions at events by Ammons, ms. and ts., n.d. (Box 84, Folder 14)
  - Teaching activities: letters and papers by students, class rosters, letters of recommendation for students, n.d., 1972, 1977, 1994 (Box 84, Folder 15)
  - Students' evaluations, n.d. (Box 84, Folder 16)
  - Departmental affairs (Cornell University) ms. and ts. correspondence and forms, n.d., 1995 (Box 84, Folder 17)
  - Talks: "Remarks for Fenn College tape", 3-Jun-62 (Box 84, Folder 18)
  - Speeches, ms. and ts., mostly n.d. (Box 84, Folder 19)
  - Interviews, ts. transcripts, n.d. (Box 84, Folder 20)
  - Other activities: painting. Invitations (rough draft), n.d. (Box 84, Folder 21)
- Series VII. Broadcasts, Recordings, and Readings
  - A.R. Ammons Memorial Service, Wait Chapel, Wake Forest University, April 19, 2001; VHS Tape V-7023 (Box 124)
  - A.R. Ammons MFA Writing, October 2, 2001; tr-10093; audio cassette (Box 124)
  - To Sing is Everything: The Voice of A.R. Ammons (poems and songs), CD-216 (Box 126)
  - Tape Reel 7700 Sides 1 and 2, CD-217-218 (Box 126)
    Use Copy
  - Tape Reel 7699, CD-219 (Box 126)
  - Tape Reel 7697, CD-220 (Box 126)
  - Tape Reel 7702, CD-221 (Box 126)
  - Tape Reel 7703, CD-222 (Box 126)
  - Tape Reel 7704 Sides 1 and 2, CD-223-224 (Box 126)
  - Tape Reel 7705, CD-225 (Box 126)
  - Tape Reel 7706, CD-226 (Box 126)
  - Phyllis and Archie Ammons singing plus poetry talk, CD-356 (Box 126)
  - Winter with Writers-Rollins Archives, January 17, 1989; CD-1385 (Box 126)
  - Center, CD-2047 (Box 126)
    1. Center 2. Transfer 3. Making - Music by Thomas DeLio, Text by A.R. Ammons
  - The Poet's Cafe with A.R. Ammons, VHS V-386 (Box 128)
  - Focus on Poetry: A.R. Ammons, VHS V-405 (Box 128)
  - A.R. Ammons Symposium; Sunday Morning with Alice Fulton, VHS V-406 (Box 128)
  - Witness: The Ecological Poetry of W.S. Merwin, VHS V-407 (Box 128)
  - A.R. Ammons rough cut - North Carolina awards, VHS V-408 (Box 128)
  - "The Author, the Poet, The Columbus County Native" A.R. Ammons, VHS V-409 (Box 128)
  - Easter Morning, VHS V-410 (Box 128)
  - "Easter Morning, A.R. Ammons and his poem", VHS V-411 (Box 128)
  - A.R. Ammons, segment for Focus on Art series, VHS V-412 (Box 128)
  - Ammonsfest - Cornell University. Poetryfor A.R. Ammons, April 3, 1998; VHS V-491 (Box 128)
  - Stewart Park, A.R. Ammons, Compact U-matic V-413 (Box 128)
  - A.R. Ammons interview, U-matic V-706 (Box 128)
  - Stucky: Four Poems of A.R. Ammons, tr-7677a; audio cassette (Box C-14)
  - Bird by Bird, on poems by A.R. Ammons, tr-7678a; audio cassette (Box C-14)
  - Interview for Poetry Magazine with Alice Fultona and Joseph Parisi, tr-7679a; audio cassette (Box C-14)
  - New Letters on the Air: A.R. Ammons, tr-7680a; audio cassette (Box C-14)
  - "Oreo Joe Fuss" performed by A.R. Ammons, tr-7681a; audio cassette (Box C-14)
  - Cornell Forum: "In Search of the Sufficient" a talk with A.R. Ammons, tr-7682a; audio cassette (Box C-14)
  - Three A.R. Ammons songs for a cappella chorus, tr-7683a; audio cassette (Box C-14)
  - Modern American Poetry Criticism: A.R. Ammons, tr-7684a; audio cassette (Box C-14)
  - Raft: One Reading of a Poem of A.R. Ammons, with note from Ann Silsbee, tr-7685a; audio cassette (Box C-14)
  - Poets in Person: Intro and Allen Ginsburg, tr-7686a; audio cassette (Box C-14)
  - Poets in Person: Karl Shapiro and Maxine Kumin, tr-7687a; audio cassette (Box C-14)
  - Scott Joplin and Jelly Roll Morton, tr-7688a; audio cassette (Box C-14)
  - Cathy Marker: Configurations, tr-7689a; audio cassette (Box C-14)
  - Don Freund: Radical Light after the poem by A.R. Ammons, tr-7690a; audio cassette (Box C-14)
  - Student settings of "Time Spans", tr-7691a; audio cassette (Box C-14)
  - Kenneth Frazelle: Sunday at McDonald's, tr-7692a; audio cassette (Box C-14)
  - Kenneth Frazelle: Still, tr-7693a; audio cassette (Box C-14)
  - Kenneth Frazelle: Worldly Hopes, tr-7694a; audio cassette (Box C-14)
  - Kenneth Frazelle: Seascapes, tr-7695a; audio cassette (Box C-14)
  - A.R. Ammons reading four poems at Epoch Literary Festival, tr-7696a; audio cassette (Box C-14)
  - A.R. Ammons interviewed by Alice Fulton, March 29, 1990, tr-7757a; audio cassette (Box C-15)
  - Late Christmas Eve, 1977; Ammons poems read by Ammons, July 20, 1970, tr-7758a; audio cassette (Box C-15)
  - Hymn: poem of A.R. Ammons, tr-7697; audio tape (reel) (Box 132)
    Use CD-220 in Box 126
  - Hymn II: poem of A.R. Ammons, tr-7698; audio tape (reel) (Box 132)
  - A.R. Ammons Reading, tr-7699; audio tape (reel) (Box 132)
    Use CD-219 in Box 126
  - Phyllis and Archie Ammons singing, tr-7700; audio tape (reel) (Box 132)
    Use CD-217 and 218 in Box 126
  - Uplands: Three Mountain Songs by A.R. Ammons, tr-7701; audio tape (reel) (Box 132)
  - Interview with A.R. Ammons, poet, tr-7702; audio tape (reel) (Box 132)
    Use CD-221 in Box 126
  - readings of poems by A.R. Ammons, tr-7703; audio tape (reel) (Box 132)
    Use CD-222 in Box 126
  - Phyllis and Archie Ammons singing plus poetry talk, tr-7704; audio tape (reel) (Box 132)
    Use CD-223-224 in Box 126
  - Seven poets reading their work (including Ammons), tr-7705; audio tape (reel) (Box 132)
    Use CD-225 in Box 126
  - Phyllis and Archie Ammons singing, tr-7706; audio tape (reel) (Box 132)
    Use CD-226 in Box 126
  - unmarked 1, tr-7707; audio tape (reel) (Box 132)
  - unmarked 2, tr-7708; audio tape (reel) (Box 132)
  - A. R. Ammons: "A few words about poetry" 1962, tr-8668; reel (Box 132)
  - Passages (poetry reading), 1981; tr-7998a; audio cassette (Box C-18)
  - "Soundings" from the National Humanities Center "Literary Inquiry Today, 1986; tr-7999a; audio cassette (Box C-18)
  - "Soundings" from the National Humanities Center "Poets on Poetry", 1986; tr-8000a; audio cassette (Box C-18)
  - Kenneth Frazelle: Blue Ridge Airs, 1988; tr-8001a; audio cassette (Box C-18)
  - Alberto Rios poetry reading, 1990; tr-8002a; audio cassette (Box C-18)
  - Poets in Person: Gary Soto interview with Joseph Parisi; A. R. Ammons interview with Alice Fulton, 1991; tr8003a; audio cassette (Box C-18)
  - Steven Stucky: Pinturas de Tamayo, 1995; tr-8004a; audio cassette (Box C-18)
  - Epoch Festival: Poetry Reading, 1997; tr8005a; audio cassette (Box C-18)
  - Ammons - piano (2), tr-8006a; audio cassette (Box C-18)
  - Steven Stucky: Four Poems of A. R. Ammons, tr-8007a; audio cassette (Box C-18)
  - Mechanism, tr-8008a; audio cassette (Box C-18)
  - The Pieces of My Voice, A.R.A., music: David C. Meckler, tr-8009a; audio cassette (Box C-18)
  - Seventeen Songs from 35@35 - Scearce, tr-8010a; audio cassette (Box C-18)
  - Windswept (the trees), tr-8011a; audio cassette (Box C-18)
  - Kenneth Frazelle: Sonata for Cello and Piano, tr-8012a; audio cassette (Box C-18)
  - Dan Locklair: Choral Music based on poetry by A.R. Ammons, CD-1
- Series VIII. Honors, Awards, and Prizes
  - Bolligen Prize (1973/1974) [two ts. letters], January 20, 1975; January 29, 1975 (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - "Garbage" ["for the Kingsley Tufts Poetry Award"] ts., December 8, 1993 (Box 85, Folder 2)
  - National Book Award (1993) correspondence, clippings, event programme, photographs, various dates (Box 85, Folder 3)
  - Frost Silver Medal (1994) [two ts. letters], December 15, 1993; April 6, 1994 (Box 85, Folder 4)
  - Pushcart Prize XX (1994) (Box 85, Folder 5)
  - Ruth Lilly Poetry Prize (1995) ad, photocopy (Box 85, Folder 6)
  - Certificates and announcements, various dates (Box 85, Folder 7)
  - Awards (certificates), various dates (Box 116, Folder 2)
  - National Book Award, 1993; MU-1136 (Box 118)
  - American Academy of Letters, 1996-2000 (Box 121, Folder 1)
  - North Carolina Literary Hall of Fame, 1996-2000 (Box 121, Folder 2)
- Series IX. Critical Reception
  - Essays and Articles
    - Culler, Jonathan [?]. "Reading Garbage," November 7, 1996; 1979-1996 (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - Cushman, Steve. "Pray Without Ceasing and the Postmodern Canon." University of Virginia. n. d.________, The Sublime Geometry of Ammons' Sphere., submitted to Professor Bloom, January 16, 1979. (Box 86, Folder 2)
    - Gertner, Jon "A.R. Ammons Profile", n.d. (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - Gilbert, Roger. "A.R. Ammons", n.d. (Box 86, Folder 4)
    - Vendler, Helen "The Snow Poems and Garbage: Episodes in an Evolving Poetics" two versions, n.d. (Box 86, Folder 5)
    - Book reviews. Clippings, various dates (Box 86, Folder 6)
    - ThesesFried, Philip. "Three Essays on the Poetry of A. R. Ammons." December 1978 [Includes letter introducing thesis and poem, "Unwatched Birds," April 21, 1979., 1978, 1979 (Box 86, Folder 7)
    - McFee, Michael. "Form in the Long Poems of A. R. Ammons", n.d. (Box 86, Folder 8)
    - McFee, Michael. "Summer Session 1980", n.d. (Box 86, Folder 9)
    - A.R. Ammons as subject of English courses: Responses to A.R. Ammons by Alice Fulton's students; Tests, n.d. (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Students' papers, various dates (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - Introductions to Ammons' Appearances at Readings and Events (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - [Entries in biographical dictionaries] (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - Review of Glare, 1997 (Box 122, Folder 5)
  - Clippings
    - Clippings: Articles and reviews from magazines and newspapers (Box 88)
    - News clippings, 1974 (Box 121, Folder 3)
    - News clippings, 1978-Spring 1989 (Box 121, Folder 4)
    - News clippings, July 1990-1992 (Box 121, Folder 5)
    - News clippings, 1994-1995 (Box 121, Folder 6)
    - News clippings, 1996-1997 (Box 121, Folder 7)